Elsie Clews Parsons Papers 1835-1944 Mss.Ms.Coll.29
American Philosophical Society
- Elsie Clews Parsons Papers II, 1898-1937
  - Series VIII. Photographs and Scrapbooks, [ca.1885?]-1935; 1963
    - Santa Ana - "French Soldiers" dance, Feb. 1929; 1 print (Box Papers-II Series-VIII: 3)
    - San[to] Domingo, [1923?]; n.d.; 2 prints (Box Papers-II Series-VIII: 3)
    - [Scrapbook], [1887-99?] (Box Papers-II Series-VIII: 3)
    - Spain, 1928; 41 postcards (Box Papers-II Series-VIII: 3)
    - "Spanish Elements in the Kachina Cult of the Pueblos", 1930; 5 postcards (Box Papers-II Series-VIII: 3)
    - Stephen, Alexander M., 1903; 1 mounted print (Box Papers-II Series-VIII: 3)
    - Stonover Farm (Lenox, Mass.) (Box Papers-II Series-VIII: 3)
      - Folder #1, ca. 1907; 1 print; 1 neg. (Box Papers-II Series-VIII: 3)
      - Folders #2-3, 1918; 4 prints (Box Papers-II Series-VIII: 3)
      - Folder #4, 1919; 1 print (Box Papers-II Series-VIII: 3)
    - Taft, William Howard, 1905 (Box Papers-II Series-VIII: 4)
      -See Ser. VIII, [Taft Congressional Junket...]
    - [Taft Congressional Junket to the Philippines and Japan], 1905 (Box Papers-II Series-VIII: 4)
      - Folder #1, 2 prints; 2 neg. (Box Papers-II Series-VIII: 4)
        - Parsons, Elsie Clews (Box Papers-II Series-VIII: 4)
        - Parsons, Herbert [husband] (Box Papers-II Series-VIII: 4)
        - Taft, William Howard (Box Papers-II Series-VIII: 4)
          -See also Ser. VIII, Parsons, Elsie Clews, 1905
      - Folder #2, 5 prints; 2 neg. (Box Papers-II Series-VIII: 4)
        - Taft, William Howard (Box Papers-II Series-VIII: 4)
      - Folders #3-8, 168 neg. (Box Papers-II Series-VIII: 4)
    - Taos, [1923?]; n.d.; 2 prints (Box Papers-II Series-VIII: 4)
      - True, Clara D. - Home in Santa Fe, N.M., n.d.; 1 print (Box Papers-II Series-VIII: 4)
    - Toor, Frances, 1930 (Box Papers-II Series-VIII: 4)
      -See Ser. VIII, Parsons, Elsie Clews, 1930
    - Unidentified (Box Papers-II Series-VIII: 4)
      - 3 Folders, n.d.; 20 prints; 3 neg. (Box Papers-II Series-VIII: 4)
    - Villarán, Benjamin, Jr., 1930; 1 print (Box Papers-II Series-VIII: 4)
    - Washington, D.C. House, 1 postcard (Box Papers-II Series-VIII: 4)
    - Zuni, [1923?]; 2 prints (Box Papers-II Series-VIII: 4)
    - Zuni - Notes, [Feb. 1918?]; 3 prints (Box Papers-II Series-VIII: 4)
  - Series IX. Financial Records, 1906-1941
    primarily contains accounts with banks and stock brokers (mostly dating after Herbert's death in 1925) and domestic bills and receipts (1906-1928). The bills and receipts are arranged by type of alphabetical order by type of material (e.g. Accounts), and then in alphabetical order by folder title, and then in chronological order.
    - Accounts (Box Papers-II Series-IX: 1)
      - Accounts - Bankers Trust Co., 1926-39 (Box Papers-II Series-IX: 1)
      - Accounts - Henry Clews & Co. (Box Papers-II Series-IX: 1)
        - Folder #1, 1925-26 (Box Papers-II Series-IX: 1)
        - Folder #2, 1928-32 (Box Papers-II Series-IX: 1)
        - Folder #3, 1933; 1936 (Box Papers-II Series-IX: 1)
      - Accounts - Estate of Herbert Parsons, 1927; 1929 (Box Papers-II Series-IX: 1)
      - Accounts - Guaranty Trust Co. of New York, 1909-12; 1920 (Box Papers-II Series-IX: 1)
      - Accounts - Mabon & Co., 1906-09; 1924-25 (Box Papers-II Series-IX: 1)
      - Accounts - Mabon & Co. - Balance Sheets, 1906-12; 1925 (Box Papers-II Series-IX: 1)
      - Accounts - Parsons, Closson & McIlvaine (Box Papers-II Series-IX: 1)
        - Folder #1, 1909-28 (Box Papers-II Series-IX: 1)
        - Folder #2, 1929-32 (Box Papers-II Series-IX: 1)
      - Accounts - G.P. Putnam's Sons, 1916-19 (Box Papers-II Series-IX: 1)
      - Accounts - Wilsey Investment Co., 1925-27 (Box Papers-II Series-IX: 1)
        (end of Accounts)
    - Bills and receipts (Box Papers-II Series-IX: 1)
      - Folder #1, 1906-11 (Box Papers-II Series-IX: 1)
      - Folder #2, Jan.-Nov. 1912 (Box Papers-II Series-IX: 1)
      - Folder #3, Dec. 1912 (Box Papers-II Series-IX: 1)
      - Folder #4, Jan. 1913 (Box Papers-II Series-IX: 1)
      - Folder #5, Feb.-Mar. 1913 (Box Papers-II Series-IX: 1)
      - Folder #6, Apr.-Dec. 1913 (Box Papers-II Series-IX: 1)
      - Folder #7, Jan.-Sep. 1914 (Box Papers-II Series-IX: 1)
      - Folder #8, Oct.-Nov. 1914 (Box Papers-II Series-IX: 2)
      - Folder #9, Dec. 1914 (Box Papers-II Series-IX: 2)
      - Folder #10, Jan. 1915 (Box Papers-II Series-IX: 2)
      - Folder #11, Feb.-Mar. 1915 (Box Papers-II Series-IX: 2)
      - Folder #12, Apr.-May 1915 (Box Papers-II Series-IX: 2)
      - Folder #13, 1917-33; 1941 (Box Papers-II Series-IX: 2)
    - Estate of John E. Parsons, 1917 (Box Papers-II Series-IX: 2)
    - Guardianships, 1928-30; n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-IX: 2)
    - Income Tax Calculations (Box Papers-II Series-IX: 2)
      - Folder #1, [1924?] (Box Papers-II Series-IX: 2)
      - Folder #2, 1926 (Box Papers-II Series-IX: 2)
    - Malabar V (ship), 1932 (Box Papers-II Series-IX: 2)
      -See also Ser.X, Corr. - Conway, J.A.
      -See also Ser.X, Corr. - Wm. Edgar John & Co.
      -See also Ser.X, Corr. - Parsons, McIlvaine
      -See also Ser.X, Malabar V
    - Pajarito Ranch, N.M., 1921-23 (Box Papers-II Series-IX: 2)
      - Edwards, A.M. (Box Papers-II Series-IX: 2)
      - Herrick, Robert (Box Papers-II Series-IX: 2)
      - Law, George (Box Papers-II Series-IX: 2)
        -See also Ser.I, Law, George
    - Record of Investments and Income (Box Papers-II Series-IX: 2)
    - Securities, 1919; 1926 (Box Papers-II Series-IX: 2)
    - Stocks, 1910-36 (Box Papers-II Series-IX: 2)
    - Yacht Charter [for "Hardi Biaou"], 21 Oct. 1926 (Box Papers-II Series-IX: 2)
  - Series X. Estate of Elsie Clews Parsons, 1927-1967
    contains correspondence and account information related to the settlement of Parsons' estate. The principal executors were John Parsons and Elsie Parsons Kennedy, though Herbert and McIlvaine conducted some estate business. The series is organized alphabetically by type of material (e.g., Accounts), and then in alphabetical order by folder title, and then in chronological order. The bulk dates for the material in this series are from 1942 to 1945.
    - Accounts (Box Papers-II Series-X: 1)
      - Accounts - Bankers Trust Co. - Advice slips, 1942 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 1)
      - Accounts - Bankers Trust Co. - Correspondence, 1942-53 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 1)
      - Accounts - Chemical Bank & Trust Co., 1954-55 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 1)
      - Accounts - Henry Clews & Co. - Advice slips and receipts, 1942-47 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 1)
      - Accounts - Henry Clews & Co. - Broker's statements, 1941-47 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 1)
        -See also Ser.X, Taxes
      - Accounts - Henry Clews & Co. - Correspondence, 1941-46 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 1)
      - Accounts - Grove, Palmer & Co., Inc. - Receipts, 1943 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 1)
      - Accounts - Parsons Trading Co., 1953 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 1)
        -See also Ser.X, Corr. - Plyley, Chauncey A.
    - Assets, 1940-45 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 1)
    - Clippings, 1941 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 1)
    - Correspondence (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - Aetna Casualty and Surety Co., 1942 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - American Car and Foundry Co., 1942; 1944 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - American Folklore Society, Inc., 1942 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
        - Davidson, D.S. (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
          -See also Ser.I, American Folklore Society
          -See also Ser.X, Corr. - Parsons, Closson & McIlvaine
          -See also Ser.X, Corr. - Reichard, Gladys A.
          -See also Ser.X, Publications
      - Correspondence - Ames Shipbuilding and Drydock Co., 1942-50; n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - Anderson, Clinton P., 1942 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - Appel, Paul P., 1967 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - J.J. Augustin, Inc., 1942-58 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - Baltimore and Ohio Railroad Co., 1945 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - Bankers Safe Deposit Co., 1942 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - F.A. Bartlett Tree Expert Co., 1940-42 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
        -See also Ser.II, Bartlett Tree Expert Co.
      - Correspondence - Benedict, Ruth, 1942 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
        -See also Ser.I, Benedict, Ruth
      - Correspondence - Bird, Alan L., 1942 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - Bird, Henry, 1945 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - Charles W. Bliven & Co., 1943 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - Boas, Franz, 1942 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - Brogan, Maud, 1942 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - Brown, Wheelock, Harris, Stevens, Inc., 1942 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - Bull, Will[ia]m L., 1942 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
        -See also Ser.X, Parsons, Closson & McIlvaine
      - Correspondence - Campbell, Louise, 1942 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
        - Parsons, John (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - Central Aguirre Associates, 1942 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - Chase Safe Deposit Co., 1942 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - City & Suburban Homes Co., 1943-52 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - Colonial Families of America, 1942 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - Consolidated Edison Co., 1942; 1946 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - Conway, J.A. (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
        - [Parsons], John [E.] (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
          -See also Ser.X, Corr. - Palmer, William P.
        - Folder #1, 1941-May 1942 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
        - Folder #2, Jun. 1942-46 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - Davidson, D.S. (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
        -See Ser.X, Corr. - American Folklore Society
      - Correspondence - Dorson, Richard M., 1959-60 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - Douglas L. Elliman & Co., 1942 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - Equitable Appraisal Co., Inc., 1942 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - Freeborn & Co., 1942 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - General Store (North Haven, Maine), 1942 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - Goldfrank, Esther S., 1954-60 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
        -See also Ser.I, Goldfrank, Esther
      - Correspondence - Great Atlantic and Pacific Tea Co., 1942 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - Great Western Sugar Co., 1942-44 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - Robert Heard Hale, 1945 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - Hare, Betty, 1945 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - Hibbard, Charles L., 1942-46 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
        -See also Ser.X, Corr. - Milbank, Tweed & Hope
      - Correspondence - Hudson Trust Co., 1944-45 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - Huron Holding Corp., 1946-55 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - Industrial Trust Co., 1942 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - Internal Revenue Service, 1942-46 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - Jackson, L.C., 1958 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - Wm. Edgar John & Assoc., Inc. (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
        - Folder #1, 1942 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
        - Folder #2, 1943-46 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - Jones & Laughlin Steel Corp., 1945 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - Kennedy, Elsie Parsons (Lissa) (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
        - Realty Company of the Women's University Club (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
          -See also Ser.X, Corr. - Hare, Betty
          -See also Ser.X, Corr. - Page, Anne
        - Folder #1, Jan.-Mar. 1942 (Box Paper-II Series-X: 2)
        - Folder #2, Apr.-Dec. 1942 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
        - Folder #3, 1943-45 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
        - Folder #4, 1946-60 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - Keweenaw Land Association, Ltd., 1941-46 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - Kroeber, Alfred L., 1945 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
        -See also Ser.I, Kroeber, Alfred
      - Correspondence - Laclede Gas Light Co., 1945 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - La Guardia, F.H., 1942 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - Lenox Library Association, 1945 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - Lenox National Bank (Lenox, Mass.), 1941-42 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - Linton, Ralph, 1942 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
        -See also Ser.I, American Anthropolgist
      - Correspondence - Loesch, George, 1942 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - Luhan, Mabel Dodge, 1945 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - McGee, John, 1942 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - Maine. Industrial Accident Commission, 1942 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - Manufacturers Trust Co., 1944-45 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - Stephen Merritt Burial and Cremation Co., 1941 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - Milbank, Tweed & Hope, 1941-42 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
        - Hibbard, Charles L. (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - Murra, John, 1945 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - Nagle, Anne, 1942-49 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
        -See also Ser.II, Nagle, Anne
      - Correspondence - The New School, 1953 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - New York Hospital, 1942 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - New York State. Dept. of Labor, Division of Placement and Unemployment Insurance, 1942-43 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - New York Telephone, 1942-43 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - New York Times, 1943 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - Nielson, Sophie, 1942 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - North Haven Casino, 1942 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - Page, Anne, 1945 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
        aunt of EPK
        - Kennedy, Elsie Parsons (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - Palmer, William P., 1946 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
        - Conway, J.A. (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - Parsons, Fanny (Mrs. John E.), 1943 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
        -See also Ser.X, Corr. - Parsons, Margaret W.
      - Correspondence - Parsons, Herbert (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
        - [Parsons], Mc[Ilvaine] (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
        - Reichard, Gladys A. (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
        - Folder #1, 1942 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
        - Folder #2, 1946-60 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - Parsons, John E., 1942-58 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
        -See also Ser.X, Corr. - Campbell, Louise
      - Correspondence - Parsons, McIlvaine, 1942-60 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
        -See also Ser.X, Corr. - Parsons, Herbert
      - Correspondence - Parsons, Margaret W. (Mrs. Herbert), 1942-46; n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
        - Parsons, Fanny (Mrs. John E.) (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - Parsons, Closson & McIlvaine (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
        - American Folklore Society (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
        - Bull, William L. (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
        - Freeborn & Co. (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
        - Realty Company of the Women's University Club (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
        - Redfield, Richard (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
        - University of Chicago Press (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
        - Folder #1, 1941-Mar. 1942 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
        - Folder #2, Apr.-Dec. 1942 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
        - Folder #3, 1943-45 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
        - Folder #4, 1946-50 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - Pennroad Corp., 1945 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - L.C. Peters Shop (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - Phillips, Philip R., 1958 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - Phipps, W[illia]m A. Pond, 1942 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - Plyley, Chauncey A., 1952-53 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - Porcupine Land Association, Ltd., 1941-46 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - Pressed Steel Car Co., Inc., 1945 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - Prince & Ripley, Inc., 1942 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
        - Winthrop, Stimson, Putnam & Roberts (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - Realty Company of the Women's University Club, 1942 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
        -See also Ser.I, Women's University Club
        -See also Ser.X, Corr. - Kennedy, Elsie Parsons
      - Correspondence - Redfield, Robert (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
        - Reichard, Gladys (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
        - Folder #1, 1942 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
        - Folder #2, 1943-45 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 2)
      - Correspondence - Reichard, Gladys, 1942-49 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 3)
        - American Folklore Society, Inc. (Box Papers-II Series-X: 3)
        - Redfield, Robert (Box Papers-II Series-X: 3)
        - Rydal Press (Box Papers-II Series-X: 3)
      - Correspondence - Root, Lin, 1951 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 3)
      - Correspondence - Rydal Press (Box Papers-II Series-X: 3)
        -See Ser.X, Corr. - Reichard, Gladys
      - Correspondence - Rye (N.Y.). Board of Assessors, 1942 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 3)
      - Correspondence - Rye (N.Y.). City Clerk, 1942 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 3)
      - Correspondence - Saarinen, Aline B., 1959-60 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 3)
      - Correspondence - Charles Scribner's Sons, 1942 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 3)
      - Correspondence - Serven, James E., 1958 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 3)
      - Correspondence - Sheffield Farms Co., Inc., 1942 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 3)
      - Correspondence - Siedle, Edward V., 1942-44 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 3)
      - Correspondence - Smithsonian Institution, 1958 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 3)
      - Correspondence - P. Stammer & Son, 1942 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 3)
      - Correspondence - Standard Oil Company of California, 1942 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 3)
      - Correspondence - G.E. Stechert & Co., 1942 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 3)
      - Correspondence - F.W. Stillman Co., 1942-47 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 3)
        -See also Ser.II, Stillman Co.
      - Correspondence - Stokes, Anson Phelps, 1945 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 3)
        -See also Ser.I, Stokes, Anson
      - Correspondence - Superintendent [of 320 E.72nd St. apartment building], 1942 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 3)
      - Correspondence - Thousand Island Bridge Authority, 1943 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 3)
      - Correspondence - Torrey, J. Howard, 1942-52 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 3)
      - Correspondence - Towne Securities Corp., 1942-46 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 3)
      - Correspondence - Travelers Insurance Co., 1942 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 3)
      - Correspondence - Tybor Stores, Inc., 1947 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 3)
      - Correspondence - University of California Press, 1953 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 3)
        -See also Ser.I, University of California Press
      - Correspondence - University of Chicago, 1943 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 3)
        -See also Ser.I, University of Chicago
      - Correspondence - University of Chicago Press, 1944-49 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 3)
      - Correspondence - University of Oregon. Library, 1967 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 3)
      - Correspondence - Veterans Administration, 1942 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 3)
      - Correspondence - Viking Press Inc., 1941-49 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 3)
        -See also Ser.I, Viking Press Inc.
      - Correspondence - Wallis, Wilson D., 1939-43 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 3)
        -See also Ser.I, Wallis, Wilson
      - Correspondence - White, Leslie A., 1936; 1942 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 3)
        - Linton, Ralph (Box Papers-II Series-X: 3)
        - Spiers, Leslie (Box Papers-II Series-X: 3)
      - Correspondence - Winthrop, Stimson, Putnam & Roberts, 1942-47 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 3)
        -See also Ser.X, Corr. - Prince & Ripley, Inc.
      - Correspondence - Wittfogel, Esther Goldfrank (Box Papers-II Series-X: 3)
        -See Ser.X, Corr. - Goldfrank, Esther S.
      - Correspondence - Zimmerman, Thomas L., Jr., 1946 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 3)
        (end of Correspondence)
    - Death Certificate [of ECP], 1946 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 3)
      photostat. copies
    - Distribution of estate, 1942-50 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 3)
    - Distribution - original receipts for shares, 1945-50 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 3)
    - Distribution, [Final], 1952 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 3)
    - Estate Activity - Summaries, 1942-45 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 3)
    - Estate Tax Return - Federal, 1942-44 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 3)
    - Estate Tax Return - New York State, 1943-44 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 3)
    - Malabar V [yacht] - Sale, 1943-53 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 3)
      -See also Ser.X, Corr. - F.W. Stillman Co.
    - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-X: 3)
    - Probate - Maine, 1942-43 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 3)
    - Probate - Massachusetts, 1942 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 3)
    - Publications, 1939-44 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 3)
    - Taxes, 1941-44 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 3)
      - Henry Clews & Co. (Box Papers-II Series-X: 3)
        -See also Ser.X, Estate Tax Ret.
    - Vinal Haven, Maine - Deed of Property, 1927 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 3)
    - Will [of ECP], 1938; 1942 (Box Papers-II Series-X: 3)
  - Series III to X. Oversized, 1889-1947; 1 box (Oversize 1)
    - Series III, Lectures and Manuscripts (Oversize 1)
      - -Mss. - A Romantic in Bengal and in New York, 1925 (Oversize 1)
      - -Mss. - Alexander Stephen's Hopi Journal, [ca.1936] (Oversize 1)
    - Series IV, Research Notes and Notebooks (Oversize 1)
      - -Hindu - Notes, [1923] (Oversize 1)
      - -[Indians of North America] (Oversize 1)
      - -[Laguna, Border of church in?], n.d. (Oversize 1)
      - -Mexico - Notes, 1929-30; 1932 (Oversize 1)
      - -Nova Scotia - Notebook #1, 1923 (Oversize 1)
      - -Nova Scotia - Notes, 1923 (Oversize 1)
      - -Pueblo Indian Culture, Distribution (Oversize 1)
      - -[Pueblo Indians, Ceremonial Organization and Ceremonies] (Oversize 1)
      - -Pueblo Indians, Distribution of Rites (Oversize 1)
      - -Zuni - Notebook, 1923 (Oversize 1)
    - Series V, Herbert Parsons Papers (Oversize 1)
      - -Parsons, Herbert. Trip to Yosemite, 1910 (Oversize 1)
    - Series VII, Ephemera (Oversize 1)
      - -Calendar, 1924 (Oversize 1)
      - -Concert Programs, 1889-90; 1919 (Oversize 1)
      - -[Italian Art], n.d. (Oversize 1)
    - Series VIII, Photographs and Scrapbooks (Oversize 1)
      - -Luhan, Mabel Dodge - House, n.d. (Oversize 1)
      - -Parsons, Elsie Clews, [ca.1885?] (Oversize 1)
        5 mounted prints
      - -Parsons, Elsie Clews, 1902 (Oversize 1)
        2 mounted prints
      - -Parsons, Elsie (Lissa) and Elsie Clews Parsons, 1902 (Oversize 1)
        1 mounted print
      - -Unidentified, n.d. (Oversize 1)
      - Native American at camp site, 1888-1942
    - Series IX, Financial Papers (Oversize 1)
      - -Pajarito Ranch, N.M., 1921-23 (Oversize 1)
    - Series X, Estate of Elsie Clews Parsons (Oversize 1)
      - -Accounts - Henry Clews & Co. - Broker's Statements, 1941-47 (Oversize 1)
      - -Corr. - F.W. Stillman Co., 1942-47 (Oversize 1)